Luis Felipe López Montes

Full-stack web developer

PHP, Symfony, ReactJS, SQL, TDD, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, JIRA, SCRUM. # Python, Jupyter, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, FastAPI, Google Compute

Software engineer with two years of experience in web development, both backend and frontend. Passionate about sport, nature and coding. With objectives, among others, to achieve stability within a company in which I can put my skills into practice, as well as being able to carry out different projects in which to focus my motivation.





Austrasse 45, 8045, Zürich









PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Aircury. Full-stack web developer. 08/2022 – 10/2023 (Remote)

I worked for a UK-based customer (CEC) in the UK education sector, following Agile **SCRUM** and using **JIRA** for task management. My role involved developing the tasks required by the customer within each sprint while adhering to best practices such as **TDD** and **BDD** methodologies.

These tasks included **full-stack** development, such as creating new features, sections, and more on various web applications, using ReactJS and PHP-Symfony, as well as database management with **Doctrine** and **PostgreSQL**.

Additionally, code reviews were conducted for my teammates' tickets as well as collaboration with our support and testing teams, ensuring quality and consistency throughout the company's workflow. In addition, I also implemented automated tasks and pipelines in **Jenkins** for data integration from external platforms.

We worked with **Docker** environments running on **AWS**, along with **Kubernetes** for container orchestration and management, and Jenkins for automating the deployment process. Version control was conducted with GitHub.

Strategic Thinking. Full-stack web developer. 05/2021 – 12/2021 (Remote)

Full-stack development using Vanilla JS, HTML and CSS, using Google Firebase Firestore Database and Materialize.css. Co-founder of https://anetva2021.web.app/. and maintenance of https://totalhse.web.app/

University of Vigo. Intern. 02/2020 – 08/2020 (Ourense, Spain)

I carried out maintenance tasks and managed a computer space for study and learning through ICTs. Constantly dealing with students and employees who needed help with both computer and printer problems.

MQL5.COM. Freelancer. 12/2019 – 12/2020 (Remote)

Development of operational scripts in Forex markets, based on technical market indicators. Direct contact with customers.

Banco Santander. Bank clerk. 07/2018 – 08/2018 (Bilbao, Spain)

LANGUAGES

English: Professional (C1) French: Intermediate (B2)

Spanish: Native Galician: Native

EDUCATION

10/2023-12/2023

Data Science Bootcamp Le Wagon, Zürich (Python, SQL, Jupyter, Matplotlib, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Google Compute, Hugging Face, MLflow, EastAPI, ChatGPT)

2016-2022 **Bachelor in Computer Engineering** University of Vigo

2016-2022 **Bachelor in Business** Administration University of Vigo

PORTFOLIO

Click to see my portfolio!

OTHER DETAILS

L Swiss permit holder **EU** citizen